[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339caf", "question": "What breed of dog is McGruff?", "answer": "Bloodhound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078b640eee65b76b9f2667", "question": "Which seven U.S. states seceded and formed the original Confederacy during the U.S. Civil War?", "answer": "Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, Mississippi, South Carolina and Texas.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389ca", "question": "What decade was Agatha Christie's \"Murder on the Orient Express\" set in?", "answer": "The 1920s", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad9dcfae748bb36357acddf", "question": "In the original \"Oregon Trail\" game, made in 1971, what were the four infectious diseases that could kill members of your party?", "answer": "Typhoid, Cholera, Measles, Dysentery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a770", "question": "Before being renamed, what was Mumbai called?", "answer": "Bombay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601737fa44491cbd7c5a1791", "question": "During World War II, prisoners wearing a purple triangle in a concentration camp signified the prisoners were what?", "answer": "Primarily\u00a0Jehovah's Witnesses\u00a0and some members of other small pacifist religious groups", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a631", "question": "How many US states begin with the letter \"O\"?", "answer": "Three - Ohio, Oklahoma, and Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cad", "question": "What 2002 movie was developed under the title \"Surf Girls of Maui\"?", "answer": "Blue Crush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e7", "question": "Guitarist Dave Navarro was married for just over three years to which star of \"Baywatch\" and \"Singled Out\"?", "answer": "Carmen Electra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cc45bb53d1af658864df", "question": "How many years after the founding of the company did Hallmark release its first Christmas cards?", "answer": "5 years", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1df", "question": "The single \"Up Where We Belong\" is taken from which film?", "answer": "An Officer and a Gentleman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f9bb01dd7bf43be5e84d", "question": "What was football legend Joe Namath's nickname?", "answer": "Broadway Joe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339368", "question": "In the 1960 movie \"Psycho\", what actor plays the private detective?", "answer": "Martin Balsam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3be0ff048f679a45ab39", "question": "What organ does a deer lack?", "answer": "Gall bladder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa05", "question": "Which mountain range lies in the north of Spain, west of The Pyrenees?", "answer": "The Cantabrian Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f25", "question": "In the King James Bible, all but three books of the New Testament end with what word?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b7", "question": "The zodiac sign \"Taurus\" refers to what animal?", "answer": "The bull", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049b64cf93664eb104869f", "question": "Which producer on the TV show \"Lost\" co-created the comic book series \"Y: The Last Man\"?", "answer": "Brian K. Vaughan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ec2008d98002fdd633b7", "question": "Which singer's autobiography is titled \"Take It Like a Man\"?", "answer": "Boy George's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6003950057a0e35c43f83890", "question": "What is the term for a thin, opaque coat of paint or layer of shading applied to give a softer or duller effect?", "answer": "Scumble - A technique in which the coating is opaque, and is painted on thinly to allow bits of the paint below to shine through.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5989af08cb8751d53e7d7619", "question": "What major American city is nicknamed, \"The Mile-High City?\"", "answer": "Denver, Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b3", "question": "How many times can you fold a regular piece of paper in half?", "answer": "7", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfe0211b668d7dfe168b5ca", "question": "Who became the first father-and-son team to win Oscars for the 1948 film \"The Treasure of Sierra Madre\"?", "answer": "Walter and John Huston", "category": "entertanment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1e4", "question": "Which US president lived in Springwood?", "answer": "Franklin Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6018bd81d96d05b23b28165b", "question": "The \"girl in the polka dot dress\" was an eye witness in whose assassination?", "answer": "Robert F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4bff49076251badbeacb", "question": "Which U.S. President had the most children?", "answer": "John Tyler -- The 10th president had 16 children \u2014 15 with his two wives and one born out of wedlock.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea366cff048f679a45ab0d", "question": "What are the bones in the fingers called?", "answer": "Phalanges", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd5", "question": "What is the surname of Sesame Street's The Count?", "answer": "Von Count", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdcefec223966ae8f88fa", "question": "Which Christmas song was the second piece of music broadcast on the radio?", "answer": "\"O Holy Night\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d8", "question": "Princeton University is located in which state?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "596dfaebcf3977a46e7ce448", "question": "Bees have 5 what?", "answer": "Eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c0", "question": "What are female elephants called?", "answer": "Cows", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b8cf2994b094db915830ad", "question": "The Bical grape originates from which European country?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b04", "question": "Which goddess started the Trojan War?", "answer": "Eris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a373", "question": "What is the capital of Germany?", "answer": "Berlin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600243e54be4723ccac2219d", "question": "\"Leaves of Grass\", first published in 1855, is a poetry collection by which American poet?", "answer": "Walt Whitman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397fb", "question": "Who had a 1982 No.1 hit with \"Happy Talk\"?", "answer": "Captain Sensible", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523dca736d4be723796b48", "question": "What year did the last Province or Territory join Canada?", "answer": "1999", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59049ececf93664eb10486b6", "question": "Dogteeth tetras are a family of freshwater fishes native to what continent?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c9", "question": "What is the term for a wolf's home?", "answer": "Den", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339726", "question": "How many fingers does Mickey Mouse have?", "answer": "8", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87b", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Nathan Road\"?", "answer": "Hong Kong", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6db", "question": "A cygnet is the name for a newly hatched or baby what?", "answer": "Swan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe908d901dd7bf43be5e888", "question": "What kind of scientist was Linus Pauling?", "answer": "Chemist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab1a92baab681b09292195", "question": "What celebrity\u2019s car was fixed and raced in the 2009 documentary \u201cLove the Beast\u201d", "answer": "Eric Bana's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133930b", "question": "In Disney's movie \"The Lion King\", what does \"Hakuna Matata\" mean?", "answer": "No worries", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33d", "question": "What snack is Tallahassee searching for in the 2009 film \"Zombieland\"?", "answer": "Twinkies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3612ff048f679a45ab08", "question": "Lateral Epicondylitis is a condition commonly known by what name?", "answer": "Tennis elbow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a845", "question": "What Florida city is known as the \"Winter Strawberry Capital of the World\"?", "answer": "Plant City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fffa74f73838c5c8a417f37", "question": "What is the fear of long words known as?", "answer": "Hippopotomostrosesquippedaliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5902a125cad1ec93f27df774", "question": "What 1960\u2019s film with Michael Caine is often credited with aiding to the popularity of the French Press?", "answer": "The Ipcress File", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339716", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Homer gave up his soul for a single what?", "answer": "Doughnut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a328", "question": "Who played the role of Reggie Hammond in the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Eddie Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea0", "question": "What future star's neck is broken by Bruce Lee in the cave fight in \"Enter the Dragon\"?", "answer": "Jackie Chan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937eca808d98002fdd633be", "question": "Equatorial Guinea gained independence from which country in 1968?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab949d86faa38a764be50e", "question": "What company made the LFA?", "answer": "Lexus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8cea894b094db915830a9", "question": "What year did Google first release the Chrome web browser?", "answer": "2008", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0bb", "question": "What former Governor of Pennsylvania became the first Secretary of Homeland Security in 2003?", "answer": "Tom Ridge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff14722b0ee8c595b6d39c3", "question": "What was Sleeping Beauty poisoned by?", "answer": "A spindle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be14", "question": "What does a DNR order at a hospital stand for?", "answer": "Do Not Resuscitate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d5", "question": "What manager founded the Backstreet Boys and *NSYNC?", "answer": "Lou Pearlman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58bb3229e368446ca7bd6841", "question": "Which chemical element has the highest boiling point?", "answer": "Tungsten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1cc", "question": "What film starred Michael Caine and Angie Dickinson?", "answer": "Dressed to Kill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66d3aa5bfecdd737e089d", "question": "What is the total face point value of all the tiles in Scrabble?", "answer": "187", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062a09c9d816e292245c12", "question": "Which German painter was best known for his depictions of naval warfare in World War I?", "answer": "Claus Bergen (1885-1964) developed a specialty of painting naval subjects, as well as fishing scenes and coastal views.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600781fabd51d85e222ab651", "question": "What is the title of Henri Matisse's famous portrait of his wife?", "answer": "In 1905, just prior to such works being derisively labeled as the creations of Les Fauves, he painted\u00a0\"The Green Stripe\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff7c3462b316f4693fb67a7", "question": "Monterey Jack is a type of what?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af7c", "question": "The Battle of Lexington occurred at the start of what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b4", "question": "What character is best known for their phrase \"What's up, Doc\"?", "answer": "Bugs Bunny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3701ff048f679a45ab12", "question": "Which Austrian psychiatrist penned \"The Interpretation of Dreams\" in 1900?", "answer": "Sigmund Freud", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c1", "question": "In atmospheres, what is the equivalent of 760 milimeters of Mercury (mmHg)?", "answer": "1 atm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e859fe83fe1f2a824bdb", "question": "Which English king built castles in the 13th century to help conquer Wales?", "answer": "Edward I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae2f", "question": "What popular figure was assassinated by Sirhan Sirhan?", "answer": "Robert F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133941b", "question": "Radiohead took the title of their album Paranoid Android from what book series?", "answer": "Hitchhikers Guide to the Galaxy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989ae68cb8751d53e7d7615", "question": "The dance called the \"Maxixe\" is also known by what name?", "answer": "Brazilian Tango", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab74", "question": "Dhaka is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f5660b33a95c66dc4fe75d", "question": "Which British opera festival was started in 1934?", "answer": "Glyndebourne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339661", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who sold a monorail to the city of Springfield?", "answer": "Lyle Lanley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5b", "question": "Which terrorist group invaded the Munich Olympic Village in 1972?", "answer": "Black September", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a8", "question": "Whose California grave marker reads \"1935 - 1998 And the Beat Goes On?\"", "answer": "Sonny Bono's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c745", "question": "In what organ of the human body is the hippocampus?", "answer": "The brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa21", "question": "Where is the Guggenheim museum?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133912c", "question": "Dale Arden, Princess Aura, and Dr. Hans Zarkov are characters from which classic American comic strip?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339161", "question": "Who was the commander of the Starship Enterprise?", "answer": "Captain James T. Kirk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049ddecf93664eb10486b1", "question": "What year was the original film \"Friday the 13th\" released?", "answer": "1980", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ca", "question": "What year did Jean Anouilh write the play \"The Lark\"?", "answer": "1952", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b376", "question": "Who was the last woman to be hanged in Britain in the 1950's?", "answer": "Ruth Ellis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e95", "question": "Whose first book was the 2006 memoir \"Peace Mom\"?", "answer": "Cindy Sheehan's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b174533bb2d29f81593b6ff", "question": "What is the fear of going to bed known as?", "answer": "Clinophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e8", "question": "What Mexican border city is located south of San Diego?", "answer": "Tijuana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae5b", "question": "What was the name of Adolf Hitler's political party (abbr.)?", "answer": "NSDAP", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a121", "question": "For which movie did director John Schlesinger receive an Oscar in 1970?", "answer": "Midnight Cowboy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e66306d333868d34d732", "question": "What did Louis Braille invent?", "answer": "A writing system for blind people", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d70", "question": "Who was originally created from a green spring coat that Elizabeth Henson had thrown out?", "answer": "Kermit the Frog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c3", "question": "What is the name for a baby turkey?", "answer": "Poult", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b647e662d71a53651005", "question": "What Danish author is considered by many to be the most prolific fairy tale writer?", "answer": "Hans Christian Andersen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac9d", "question": "How many of Henry VIII's wives were executed?", "answer": "Two", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc0c6a469bb8041d07a050", "question": "What is a group of witches called?", "answer": "A coven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7f4", "question": "What is the Bicycle brand famous for making?", "answer": "Playing cards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937e98708d98002fdd6339a", "question": "The alcoholic beverage \"Poteen\" originates from which country?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a25f1876682715b82711ce1", "question": "Pyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b0", "question": "What Oscar-winning Best Picture is named for a type of rose?", "answer": "American Beauty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abfe", "question": "Devils Tower is located in what US state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fbae4d50738315b1fb74e20", "question": "What franchise team is the oldest in professional football history in the United States?", "answer": "Arizona Cardinals", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59c", "question": "What is a male beaver called?", "answer": "A buck", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b6ece662d71a53651010", "question": "\"Lean Mean Thirteen\" was published in 2007 by which author?", "answer": "Janet Evanovich", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4bd849076251badbeac9", "question": "What country's declaration of war triggered the start of World War I?", "answer": "After Bosnian Serb Gavrilo Princip assassinated Archduke Franz Ferdinand, Austria-Hungary declared war on Serbia in July 1914.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133908c", "question": "What does the prefix \"pseudo\" mean?", "answer": "False", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f3", "question": "What US state has been governed by Benjamin Butler and Edward Everett?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339506", "question": "What does Lilo give Stitch to drink in a baby bottle?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd8", "question": "Who wrote the 1912 novel \"The Lost World\"?", "answer": "Sir Arthur Conan Doyle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f0", "question": "What classic 1951 sci-fi film features the immortal line \"Klaatu Barata Nikto\"?", "answer": "The Day the Earth Stood Still", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e96", "question": "What Tennessee Williams title character is married to Brick Pollitt?", "answer": "Maggie the Cat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff2102531a458464a93c43c", "question": "What classic novel was originally published with the title \"Fiesta\" in the U.K.?", "answer": "\"The Sun Also Rises", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be57d0b5415ba52ed6f0aa5", "question": "In which children\u2019s series is the villain named Count Olaf?", "answer": "A Series of Unfortunate Events", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c553", "question": "What is studied by nephrology?", "answer": "Kidneys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ee", "question": "What does a Scoville unit measure?", "answer": "Spiciness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf84", "question": "What is British politician William Hague's middle name?", "answer": "Jefferson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3df", "question": "Which is the only Portuguese-speaking Latin American country?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c8f", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was warned that the cow was in the corn?", "answer": "Little Boy Blue", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a51e", "question": "What river runs through both Lyon and Marseilles?", "answer": "Rhone River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d3b", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Thunder Road\"?", "answer": "Robert Mitchum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd69fa76c0f9723ab15cb2d", "question": "What was Martin Luther King, Jr.'s birth name?", "answer": "Michael", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c877", "question": "What disease does the \"tine test\" detect?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339704", "question": "Which Star Trek character is a big fan of Earl Grey tea?", "answer": "Captain Picard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac20", "question": "Suriname is part of which continent?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a928", "question": "Where is the Bowling Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Arlington, Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d3", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Da Vinci Code\"?", "answer": "Dan Brown", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe735abeec85e375820b24f", "question": "Who said, \"If you have ten thousand regulations you destroy all respect for the law.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cdf", "question": "How do Ben and Elaine get away from the church at the end of \"The Graduate\"?", "answer": "By bus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339822", "question": "What American opera singer was nicknamed \"Bubbles\"?", "answer": "Beverly Sills", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbe", "question": "Which war was fought along the 38th parallel?", "answer": "The Korean War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a17", "question": "Jamie Somers became \"The Bionic Woman\" following emergency surgery after what type of accident?", "answer": "Parachuting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b3a", "question": "In the John Cougar song \"Jack & Diane\", what are they eating outside the Tastee-Freez?", "answer": "A chili dog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecc", "question": "What rapper performs at the \"Mitch-a-palooza\" in the movie \"Old School\"?", "answer": "Snoop Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba92", "question": "What puzzle toy, invented in Hungary, was the best-\u00adselling toy of 1981?", "answer": "Rubik\u2019s Cube", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd665dca5bfecdd737e0863", "question": "What is the most expensive aircraft in the world?", "answer": "Air Force One", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6013697a1381754895396371", "question": "Which American poet won a Grammy for writing a Johnny Cash song?", "answer": "Shel Silverstein -- Best known for children's literature, he also wrote Johnny Cash's country hit, \"A Boy Named Sue\" in 1969.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe937656bd93ce3a4e5f66c", "question": "Cyberphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Computers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1c", "question": "What name did Superman have on Krypton?", "answer": "Kal-El", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb6e", "question": "Approximately how many plain chocolate Hershey's Kisses are there to a pound of chocolate?", "answer": "Approximately 100", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936b", "question": "How many Oscar nominations did the 2002 movie \"Chicago\" receive?", "answer": "Thirteen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09b", "question": "What is the fear of knowledge known as?", "answer": "Epistemophobia or gnosiophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921f", "question": "What is the collective name for Italian-made western movies?", "answer": "Spaghetti westerns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c5", "question": "What Irish city's name is Gaelic for \"black pool\"?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4dd", "question": "What do you get when you mix whiskey, sweet vermouth and angostura bitters?", "answer": "A Manhattan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b038", "question": "Instead of bombs, what did the British Royal Air Force drop on Germany in early WWII?", "answer": "Propaganda leaflets", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd2", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Hippomenes defeat in a footrace?", "answer": "Atalanta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4cf", "question": "When was the Pioneer 10 space probe launched into space?", "answer": "March 2, 1972", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc2e", "question": "What year did Barbie doll first appear on the market?", "answer": "1959", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6ba74fb6c85e9e634ff51", "question": "What branch of mathematics is named for the Latin for \"small pebble\"?", "answer": "Calculus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d0c12596a59cbdfbd380", "question": "Who said, \"Slanderers do not hurt me because they do not hit me\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133915f", "question": "Who is C3-PO's sidekick?", "answer": "R2-D2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e2", "question": "What is Japanese sake made from?", "answer": "Rice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc1e", "question": "What year was the Rubik's Cube invented?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1fd", "question": "Who is Patricia Mae Andrzejewski better known as?", "answer": "Pat Benatar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601217eb63c99d48cd169aec", "question": "In 1963, the New York Zoo\u2019s Great Ape House was home to the \"most dangerous animal in the world\" exhibit. What was the exhibit?", "answer": "A mirror", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbe", "question": "What name was given to the leather protection cowboys wore over the front of their pants?", "answer": "Chaps", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f84bfe83fe1f2a824c2b", "question": "The first Plague that befell Pharaoh of Egypt was?", "answer": "The first plague that tore through Egypt was the Nile turning into blood", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e4", "question": "The group \"April Wine\" was formed in 1969 in what country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acdb", "question": "Who is Cleveland, Ohio, named after?", "answer": "General Moses Cleveland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b358df35db0d66a186cb565", "question": "Burt Reynolds played the role of who on the TV show \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "Blacksmith Quint Asper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba40", "question": "What is the first number in the zip code for the District of Columbia?", "answer": "2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e3ccfe83fe1f2a824baa", "question": "What statement best characterizes the series of battles in the Pacific following the Battle of Guadalcanal?", "answer": "With each battle, the Japanese soldiers increasingly fought to the death", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a89a", "question": "Where would you find the King's Palace, the Papoose Room, and the Witch's Finger?", "answer": "Carlsbad Caverns", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8a", "question": "How long did Pope John Paul I serve?", "answer": "33 days", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4ae449076251badbeabd", "question": "Who earned the nickname \"Moses\" in the Underground Railroad?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman -- One of the most well-known coordinators of the Underground Railroad, she helped more than 70 slaves to freedom.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fde4d27c6c6b019850c9a7f", "question": "What did the Romans call the city now known as London?", "answer": "Londinium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec259a8dc25ca9e12ef640", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Fahrenheit 451\"?", "answer": "Ray Bradbury", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc727ec223966ae8f888b", "question": "What is the name of the device used to facilitate dream sharing in the movie \"Inception\"?", "answer": "A Portable Automated Somnacin IntraVenous Device (PASIV)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c325", "question": "What does the acronym RPM stand for?", "answer": "Revolutions per minute", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcfe", "question": "What did the letter Q originally stand for in NASDAQ?", "answer": "Quotations", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefbe546ce05a3942286eed", "question": "Which actor had a role in the Hannibal Lector films \"Manhunter,\" \"Silence of the Lambs,\" \"Hannibal\" and \"Red Dragon\"?", "answer": "Frankie Faison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c34c", "question": "What element makes up the majority of the air in Earth's atmosphere?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c07", "question": "Which character in Greek mythology had many heads", "answer": "Lernaean Hydra", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac86", "question": "What country gave the Statue of Liberty to the US?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ec", "question": "What city was the subject of a 1982 Billy Joel song about layoffs?", "answer": "Allentown", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd7", "question": "What ingredient provides the pearls in bubble tea?", "answer": "Tapioca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cb70c36f96e155acab35d2a", "question": "How much did the United States pay Russia per acre for the purchase of Alaska in 1867?", "answer": "About 2 Cents per acre", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb2e065ff7d326b622a7b", "question": "Which Apollo space mission put the first men on the moon?", "answer": "Apollo 11", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928d", "question": "What title was the movie \"Evil Dead III\" released under?", "answer": "Army of Darkness", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017349944491cbd7c5a1781", "question": "What is he maximum number of years a US president can serve in office?", "answer": "Ten years -- If he or she inherited the office after a president died or was removed with two years or less remaining in the term, he can serve two more full terms. Otherwise they are limited to one full term.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a40", "question": "What was the first name of the American artist \"Grandma Moses\"?", "answer": "Anna", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ed8", "question": "What pieces of fruit contain three princesses in Sergei Prokofiev's most famous opera?", "answer": "Oranges", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899b9360d398dc9cf7a69e", "question": "What is the atomic number of tungsten?", "answer": "74", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988a", "question": "What instrument is Questlove most famous for playing?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339211", "question": "What is the name of the president in the movie \"Mars Attacks\"?", "answer": "James Dale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedda1c6ce05a3942286d81", "question": "Red described geology as the study of what in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Red remarked that geology is the study of time and pressure.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57e", "question": "What is the capital of County Kerry, Ireland?", "answer": "Tralee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c257", "question": "In the computer world, what does the abbreviation RAM stand for?", "answer": "Random Access Memory", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a861", "question": "Which four countries share borders with Belgium?", "answer": "France, Germany, Netherlands and Luxembourg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f5", "question": "Ham is taken from what part of a pig?", "answer": "The hind leg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b76", "question": "Whose novels include \"The Chamber\", \"The Client\", and \"The Firm\"?", "answer": "John Grisham", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc17", "question": "What organization was formed to replace \"The League of Nations\"?", "answer": "United Nations", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee4", "question": "Which cabinet post did Winston Churchill hold between 1924 and 1929?", "answer": "Chancellor of the Exchequer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feba8ef7e83c707845b20cf", "question": "How many eyelids does a duck have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59decf45ea2747c8aff16d1c", "question": "How many players are there in a men's field lacrosse team?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab99cc421a8909e5c332d3a", "question": "Corsica is part of which European country?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e40", "question": "What was the real name of TV's \"Mr. WIzard\"?", "answer": "Don Herbert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba31", "question": "\"Sweet Georgia Brown\" is the signature song of what basketball team?", "answer": "Harlem Globetrotters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067a74ff9c0647b50a805a", "question": "In 2016, which vessel became the first solar-powered aircraft to circumnavigate the Earth?", "answer": "Solar Impulse 2", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c899", "question": "Chocolate's addictive properties are due to what alkaloid?", "answer": "Theobromine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe131b0e39efa6330e0fed8", "question": "Where is the Museum of Pop Culture?", "answer": "Seattle, Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133993d", "question": "Who played the role of Bud Bundy on the TV show \"Married with Children\"?", "answer": "David Faustino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b924", "question": "What publication makes weather predictions based on a secret formula developed in 1792?", "answer": "The Old Farmer's Almanac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4ea3606d333868d34d75a", "question": "In what year did Nazi Germany open its first concentration camp?", "answer": "1933", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c90d0ee52800b05cac20f0f", "question": "What is Eisoptrophobia?", "answer": "The fear of mirrors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339315", "question": "In the movie \"Easy Rider\", where did Wyatt and Billy hide their drugs?", "answer": "Their gas tanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b360", "question": "What were the wicks in the Vestal Virgins lamps allegedly made from?", "answer": "Asbestos", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddd", "question": "Who reveals \"the man behind the curtain\" in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Toto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e1", "question": "What color is the bottom strip of Egypt's flag?", "answer": "Black", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a5", "question": "What is the middle part of an atom called?", "answer": "Nucleus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b358b6d5db0d66a186cb557", "question": "Falcon State is located in which South American country?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936f", "question": "What zodiac sign is the Joker in the movie \"Batman\"?", "answer": "Pisces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b6", "question": "Which Californian national park shares its name with a U2 album?", "answer": "Joshua Tree National Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff140e0b0ee8c595b6d399f", "question": "What is the title of Salvador Dali's iconic painting of melting clocks?", "answer": "The Persistence of Memory", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600b880a1d8c1817608d53ed", "question": "In mathematics, what term describes the bottom number in a fraction?", "answer": "Denominator", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8657ec223966ae8f880f", "question": "\"TGS with Tracy Jordan\" is a fictional sketch-comedy show that is an integral part of which series?", "answer": "\"30 Rock\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a589", "question": "Which present day US state did Ponce De Leon explore?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c0", "question": "What material is produced from the gossypium shrub?", "answer": "Cotton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c56", "question": "When was the book \u201cNational Velvet\u201d first published?", "answer": "1935", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899d3f60d398dc9cf7a6ab", "question": "What is the capital of Papua New Guinea?", "answer": "Port Moresby", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f1687cf7c52aae91cc07c8", "question": "\"Cardice\" is another term for what?", "answer": "Dry ice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae0", "question": "What is the capital of Sudan?", "answer": "Khartoum", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5de", "question": "Saginaw Bay opens into what body of water?", "answer": "Lake Huron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010c1620775fa611bce67c3", "question": "Dysmorphia is a mental disorder characterized by what?", "answer": "The obsessive idea that some aspect of one's own body part or appearance is severely flawed. The obsessive idea that some aspect of one's own body part or appearance is severely flawed, and therefore, warrants exceptional measures to hide or fix it", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a38a", "question": "In which state is the Grand Canyon located in?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e0a", "question": "In Greek myth, what nine sisters are the daughters of Mnemosyne?", "answer": "The Muses", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2f", "question": "Who wrote \"The Consolation of Philosophy\" while in prison?", "answer": "Boethius", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e94cf395ea27d7a1303aece", "question": "Which rapper went platinum with his 2014 Album \"2014 Forest Hills Drive\"?", "answer": "J. Cole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b596", "question": "Which building has been nicknamed \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "GE Building", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a4f090aac110e416706f", "question": "What fruit are Kriek lambics made with?", "answer": "Cherries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b153e662d71a53650fd0", "question": "Who founded Dumbledore's Army?", "answer": "Hermione Granger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7fe5ff048f679a45ac16", "question": "What is the most dense stable element?", "answer": "Osmium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff08fd2e662d71a53650fb2", "question": "Which philosophical movement helped inspire the American Revolution?", "answer": "The Enlightenment -- It included great leaps in philosophical thought \u2014 including ideas about democracy, the social contract, and freedom.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe73d93eec85e375820b26d", "question": "What European city celebrates Christmas every year with a straw goat?", "answer": "G\u00e4vle, Sweden", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339798", "question": "Who did Michael Jackson marry in May 1994?", "answer": "Lisa Marie Pressley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e7", "question": "In the movie \"Three men and a Baby\" what was Michael's occupation?", "answer": "Cartoonist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9c", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Collinsport, Maine?", "answer": "Dark Shadows", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c531", "question": "What is the first element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac6a", "question": "What name was Haitian dictator Francois Duvalier better known by?", "answer": "Papa Doc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffe4ae447818f5674af01af", "question": "From which novel is this quote \"I am one of the few honest people I have ever known\".?", "answer": "\"The Great Gatsby\" (Nick Carraway, a main character and the narrator of the famous novel says this line early on in the story.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d08181a1c922dd1ac64bf", "question": "Ulaanbaatar is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Mongolia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff0", "question": "Which US president delivered the Gettysburg Address?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60173fea44491cbd7c5a17b8", "question": "The Battle of Austerlitz took place during which war?", "answer": "Napoleonic Wars", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e8", "question": "In which European city can you find the \"Mouth of Truth\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab99bd521a8909e5c332d30", "question": "What year was the novel \"Who Censored Roger Rabbit?\" published?", "answer": "1981", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c3e9b06ebfabb9c85d8a981", "question": "\"Four legs good, two legs bad\" is a quotation from which novel?", "answer": "Animal Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067e5aff9c0647b50a8079", "question": "What two American astronauts passed away in February of 2016?", "answer": "Edgar Mitchell and Donald E. Williams", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc5c", "question": "\"Cirque du Soleil\" hails from what country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69b0f20565ad31a57c75b", "question": "In Nazi concentration camps, a pink triangle signified the prisoner as what?", "answer": "Homosexual", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e763fe83fe1f2a824bd2", "question": "Although never taking her seat, who was the first woman to be elected to the houses of parliament in Europe?", "answer": "Countess Markievicz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f7453a9e54d890926f6f5", "question": "What is the longest river in Australia?", "answer": "The Murray River", "category": "geography"}]